My name is Anthony Maddaloni and I'm going to talk about how to use a camera flash.
Now flash photography whether it's built into your camera or external such as this flash, is a very important part of photography.
And at first I've noticed that I had a certain, I don't know, a fear of flash, I just didn't like it.
I thought it made people look unnatural, it made them look kind of pasty.
But the more I experimented with my flash and the more I learned about photography, I found that flash photography was really, really awesome.
One way I started figuring it out was that I would just take an image naturally with natural light and then I'd either put the pop up flash on my camera on, or I would experiment with my external flash and I would take the same image using the flash.
Now I would look at my flash and what type of settings are on it.
This particular flash is a 285 HV Vivitar flash.
It's color coded on the side and that let's me control how powerful this flash can be put out.
Now sometimes I can make it very weak or I can make it very strong depending upon the situation that I'm photographing in.
In my hand right here is a sync cord.
This cord is plugged into part of my camera and actually lets me be able to hold this flash or put it onto a light stand to incorporate this in my photography.
I really do love flash photography almost as much as I like natural light photography.
So this is a really important tool to have in doing your photography.
And that is how I would use flash photography.